宇宙魔方已经苏醒
The Tesseract has awakened.
它在一个渺小的世界里 人类的世界
It is on a little world, a human world.
人类想利用其能量
They would wield its power,
可只有我们的盟友会使用它 人类是痴心妄想
but our ally knows its workings as they never will.
他将作为先锋
He is ready to lead
而我们齐塔瑞人的大军则紧随其后
and our force, our Chitauri, will follow.
给他一个地球
A world will be his.
我们要全宇宙
The universe, yours.
人类何力抵抗 只能等死
And the humans, what can they do but burn?
"全体人员注意"
"All personnel,"
"已确认撤离…"
"the evacuation order has been confirmed."
(联合暗能行动)
情况有多糟
How bad is it?
长官 最糟的正是情况尚不明朗
That's the problem, sir. We don't know.
塞尔维格博士4小时前检测到宇宙魔方发出了一股能量
Dr Selvig read an energy surge from the Tesseract four hours ago.
宇航局没允许塞尔维格做测试
NASA didn't authorise Selvig to go to test phase.
他没做测试 他当时根本不在 是自动触发
He wasn't testing it. He wasn't even in the room.Spontaneous event.
宇宙魔方自行启动了
It just turned itself on?
现在达到什么能级了
Where are the energy levels now?
还在攀升
Climbing.
塞尔维格不能关掉它
When Selvig couldn't shut it down,
我们只好下令撤离
we ordered evac.
全员撤离还需多久
How long to get everyone out?
半小时内应该能撤完
Campus should be clear in the next half-hour.
再快点
Do better.
长官 撤离或许是徒劳
Sir, evacuation may be futile.
你要我喊大伙儿回去睡觉吗
We should tell them to go back to sleep?
如果控制不住宇宙魔方的能量
If we can't control the Tesseract's energy,
逃多远可能都没用
there may not be a minimum safe distance.
你去监督转移
I need you to make sure
第二阶段所有原型机
the Phase 2 prototypes are shipped out.
长官 现在还要顾及那个吗
Sir, is that really a priority right now?
地球还照常转
Until such time as the world ends,
我们就照常过
we will act as though it intends to spin on.
搬走下面全部设备
Clear out the tech below.
将第二阶段所有设备装车运走
Every piece of Phase 2 on a truck and gone.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
跟我走
With me.
博士 什么情况
Talk to me, Doctor.
局长
Director.
现在到底掌握了些什么
Is there anything we know for certain?
宇宙魔方在淘气
The Tesseract is misbehaving.
- 你在说笑吗 - 这一点也不好笑
- Is that supposed to be funny? - No, it's not funny at all.
宇宙魔方开始活动 而且不听使唤
The Tesseract is not only active, she's behaving.
你试过切断电源了吧
I assume you pulled the plug.
她自身就是能量源
She's an energy source.
我们关上电源 她又给打开了
We turn off the power, she turns it back on.
要是她达到峰值能级
If she reaches peak level...
我们不就在为此做准备吗 博士
We prepared for this, Doctor.
利用来自宇宙的能量
Harnessing energy from space.
我们还没那金刚钻
But we don't have the harness.
我的测算还差的远呢
My calculations are far from complete.
她在释放干扰和辐射
And she's throwing off interference, radiation.
没多大危害 只是低能级的伽马射线
Nothing harmful, low levels of gamma radiation.
那也可能有危害
That can be harmful.
巴顿探员呢
Where's Agent Barton?
老鹰
The Hawk?
当然是窝在巢里
Up in his nest, as usual.
巴顿探员 请回答
Agent Barton, report.
我给你这个任务
I gave you this detail
是让你盯紧这里的情况
so you could keep a close eye on things.
远点看得更清楚
Well, I see better from a distance.
看到是什么激活了她吗
Have you seen anything that might set this thing off?
博士 能量又激增了
Doctor, it's spiking again.
没有人进出
No one's come or gone.
塞尔维格没问题
And Selvig's clean.
没有与人接触或传递信息
No contacts, no IMs.
如果有谁在搞鬼
If there was any tampering, sir,
也不是我们这边的人 长官
it wasn't at this end.
什么意思
"At this end"?
魔方不是通向宇宙另一端的门吗
Yeah, the Cube is a doorway to the other end of space, right?
门从两边都能开
Doors open from both sides.
别急啊
Not yet.
先生 请放下你的矛
Sir, please put down the spear.
你还有点灵气
You have heart.
别拿走
Please don't.
我还要用呢
I still need that.
没必要把事情闹得更大了
This doesn't have to get any messier.
当然有必要
Of course it does.
我费尽周折 就是为了它
I've come too far for anything else.
我是来自阿斯加德的洛基
I am Loki, of Asgard
我肩负光荣使命
and I am burdened with glorious purpose.
洛基
Loki,
你是托尔他弟
brother of Thor.
我们跟你们毫无纠葛
We have no quarrel with your people.
蚂蚁也没去招惹靴子
An ant has no quarrel with a boot.
你要踩死我们吗
Are you planning to step on us?
其实我带来了佳音
I come with glad tidings
我要给你们解脱
of a world made free.
怎么解脱
Free from what?
终结自由
Freedom.
自由是人生的一大的骗局
Freedom is life's great lie.
如果你能承认这一点 你的内心
Once you accept that, in your heart,
就能获得安宁
you will know peace.
你嘴上说安宁
Yeah, you say "Peace,"
我倒觉得你想挑起动乱
I kind of think you mean the other thing.
头儿 弗瑞局长在拖延时间
Sir, Director Fury is stalling.
这里就要爆炸了
This place is about to blow
我们会被压在三十多米的石块之下
and drop a hundred feet of rock on us.
他想害我们被活埋
He means to bury us.
就像奥丁的法老一样
Like the pharaohs of old.
他说得对 传送门在自我坍圮
He's right. The portal is collapsing in on itself.
再有两分钟 就会达到临界状态
We've got maybe two minutes before this goes critical.
那走吧
Well, then.
我要用这些车
I need these vehicles.
- 那是谁 - 不知道
- Who's that? - They didn't tell me.
希尔
Hill!
听得到吗
Do you copy?
巴顿被黑化了…
Barton has turned.
他们抢走了宇宙魔方 拦下他们
They have the Tesseract! Shut them down!
我们走吧 别管了 算了
Okay, let's go. No, leave it. Go!
楼上撤空了 长官 得走了
We're clear upstairs, sir. You need to go.
局长
Director?
弗瑞局长 听到了吗
Director Fury, do you copy?
宇宙魔方被敌人夺走了
The Tesseract is with a hostile force.
有人负伤 希尔汇报情况
I have men down. Hill?
还有很多人被埋
A lot of men still under.
不知有多少人生还
I don't know how many survivors.
发出全局通令
Sound a general call.
所有未参与救援的人都去找那个箱子
I want every living soul not working rescue looking for that briefcase.
收到
Roger that.
科尔森 回基地去 这是7级事件
Coulson, get back to base. This is a Level Seven.
从此刻起
As of right now,
我们开战了
we are at war.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
《复仇者联盟》
今晚和我预想的不太一样
This is not how I wanted this evening to go.
我知道你是怎么想的
I know how you wanted this evening to go.
相信我
Believe me
这样好一些
this is better.
你给谁卖命
Who are you working for?
是勒曼托夫吗
Lermentov, yes?
他觉得
Does he think
我们还需要他点头
we have to go through him
才能运我们的货吗
to move our cargo?
不是索罗霍布将军负责出口生意吗
I thought General Solohob is in charge of the export business.
索罗霍布
Solohob
他就是个中间人 幌子
a bagman, a front.
过时的情报害了你
Your outdated information betrays you.
赫赫有名的黑寡妇
The famous Black Widow
也不过就是长得漂亮而已
and she turns out to be simply another pretty face.
你真觉得我漂亮吗
You really think I'm pretty?
告诉勒曼托夫 不劳他大驾
Tell Lermentov we don't need him to move the tanks.
告诉他 他玩完了
Tell him he is out.
不过
Well...
你可能得写下来了
...you may have to write it down.
找她的
It's for her.
听好了
You listen carefully...
你在114号索伦斯基广场的三楼
You're at 1-14 Silensky Plaza, 3rd floor.
距你不到13公里 有架F-22在待命
We have an F-22 exactly eight miles out.
让那女人接电话 否则你跑不到前厅
Put the woman on the phone, or I will blow up the block
我就炸平整条街
before you can make the lobby.
- 你得回来 - 你搞什么啊 我在工作
- We need you to come in. - Are you kidding? I'm working.
那边得先放放
This takes precedence.
我正在做审讯
I'm in the middle of an interrogation.
这个傻逼什么都招了
This moron is giving me everything.
我没招啊
I don't give everything.
我现在脱不开身
Look, you can't pull me out of this right now.
娜塔莎
Natasha...
巴顿被敌人黑化了
Barton's been compromised.
你等会儿
Let me put you on hold.
巴顿人呢
Where is Barton now?
- 不知道 - 他还活着吧
- We don't know. - But he's alive?
应该是的 等你回来再细说
We think so. I'll brief you on everything when you get back.
但你得先去跟大块头谈谈
But first, we need you to talk to the big guy.
科尔森 你也知道斯塔克于我
Coulson, you know that Stark
毫无信任可言
trusts me about as far as he can throw me.
不 大款我负责 大块头你负责
I've got Stark. You get the big guy.
你是谁
Who are you?
快出去
Get out!
这里有病人
There is sickness here!
你是医生吗
You're a doctor.
我爸爸昏迷不醒
My father's not waking up!
他发烧了 还一直难受的叫
He has a fever and he's moaning
但眼睛却睁不开
but his eyes won't open.
慢慢说
Slow down.
我爸爸
My father...
像他们一样
Like them?
求你了
Please.
你个笨蛋 该先收钱的
You should've got paid up front, Banner.
你不是该
You know, for a man
远离压力吗
who's supposed to be avoiding stress
怎么选这么个地方安居
you picked a hell of a place to settle.
远离压力不是我的绝招
Avoiding stress isn't the secret.
那是什么 做瑜伽吗
Then what is it? Yoga?
你把我引离市区 很明智
You brought me to the edge of the city. Smart.
这里被包围了吧
I assume the whole place is surrounded.
只有你我二人
Just you and me.
你那个小演员呢
And your actress buddy?
她也是个特工吗 这么小就干上这个了
Is she a spy, too? They start that young?
我当年也很小
I did.
你是谁
Who are you?
娜塔莎·罗曼诺夫
Natasha Romanoff.
你是来杀我的吗 罗曼诺夫小姐
Are you here to kill me, Ms Romanoff?
要知道想杀我可没那么容易
Because that's not going to work out for everyone.
不不 当然不是 我代表神盾局而来
No, of course not. I'm here on behalf of S.H.I.E.L.D.
神盾局
S.H.I.E.L.D.
他们怎么找到我的
How did they find me?
我们一直掌握着你的行踪 博士
We never lost you, Doctor.
只是没去打扰你
We've kept our distance.
甚至替你赶走了一些
Even helped keep some other interested parties
不速之客
off your scent.
为什么
Why?
尼克·弗瑞似乎信任你
Nick Fury seems to trust you.
但现在你得跟我走
But now we need you to come in.
要是我不肯呢
What if I say no?
我会说服你
I'll persuade you.
要是…那个家伙不肯呢
And what if the other guy says no?
你一年多没出过"事故"了
You've been more than a year without an incident.
你不想破这个戒吧
I don't think you want to break that streak.
我不是总能把持得住
Well, I don't every time get what I want.
博士 一场全球性的灾难可能就要降临
Doctor, we're facing a potential global catastrophe.
这正是我一心想避免的
Well, those I actively try to avoid.
这
This
是宇宙魔方
is the Tesseract.
它有毁灭整个地球的势能
It has the potential energy to wipe out the planet.
那弗瑞找我干嘛 把它吃掉吗
What does Fury want me to do, swallow it?
是要你去找它 它被夺走了
He wants you to find it. It's been taken.
它发出的伽马信号太弱 我们追踪不了
It emits a gamma signature that's too weak for us to trace.
而你是最了解伽马射线的人了
There's no one that knows gamma radiation like you do.
否则我也不会来找你
If there was, that's where I'd be.
那弗瑞不是派你来捉怪物的
So, Fury isn't after the monster?
反正他不是这么跟我说的
Not that he's told me.
他就对你知无不言吗
And he tells you everything?
去跟弗瑞谈吧 他需要你帮忙
Talk to Fury. He needs you on this.
他要把我关起来吗
He needs me in a cage?
不会把你关起…
No one's going to put you in a...
少骗我了
Stop lying to me!
抱歉 没变身呢
I'm sorry. That was me.
我就是想试试你
I just wanted to see what you'd do.
咱们好好说话
Why don't we do this the easy way
你把枪收起来
where you don't use that
那个家伙也不会乱来
and the other guy doesn't make a mess.
好吗
Okay?
娜塔莎
Natasha?
退后
Stand down.
这里没事
We're good here.
这叫只有你我
"Just you and me."
这太不像话了 局长
This is out of line, Director.
你要操控你控制不了的力量
You're dealing with forces you can't control.
议员先生 你参过战 打过仗吗
You ever been in a war, Councilman? In a firefight?
战争中哪有什么完全控制可言
Did you feel an overabundance of control?
你是说这个阿斯加德已向地球宣战了吗
You're saying that this Asgard is declaring war on our planet?
不是阿斯加德 只是洛基
Not Asgard. Loki.
他总不会孤身而战 另一个神呢
He can't be working alone. What about the other one?
他哥哥呢
His brother.
根据我们的情报 托尔不是敌人
Our intelligence says Thor is not a hostile
但他相距甚远
but he's worlds away.
我们不能指望他来帮忙
We can't depend on him to help, either.
全看我们的了
It's up to us.
所以你更该全力开发第二阶段
Which is why you should be focusing on Phase 2.
它正是为这种情况…
It was designed for exactly this...
第二阶段尚未完成 而敌人已磨刀霍霍
Phase 2 isn't ready. Our enemy is.
我们需要一支应急分队
We need a response team.
复仇者计划已被叫停了
The Avengers Initiative was shut down.
我没说复仇者联盟的事
This isn't about the Avengers.
我们看过那份名单
We've seen the list.
你手上有世界一流的秘密特工组织
You're running the world's greatest covert security network
却要把人类的命运
and you're going to leave the fate of the human race
交给一群怪胎吗
to a handful of freaks.
我根本不是这意思
I'm not leaving anything to anyone.
我们的确需要一支应急分队
We need a response team.
这些人或许孤僻 甚至不太正常
These people may be isolated, unbalanced even
但我相信只要用人得当
but I believe with the right push
他们正能给我们亟需的帮助
they can be exactly what we need.
你相信
You believe?
感情用事是不能赢得战争的 局长
War isn't won by sentiment, Director.
的确 但好兵能
No, it's won by soldiers.
没时间了
There's not enough time.
我得让她落在海里
I got to put her in the water!
你不是一个人
You won't be alone.
天啊
Oh, my God.
这家伙还活着
This guy is still alive!
失眠了
Trouble sleeping?
都睡了70年了 长官 我想我睡够了
I slept for 70 years, sir. I think I've had my fill.
那你该出门
Then you should be out,
庆祝一下 去看看花花世界
celebrating, seeing the world.
我落水时 世界还在打仗
When I went under, the world was at war.
我醒来 只听人说我们赢了
I wake up, they say we won.
却没人说我们失去了什么
They didn't say what we lost.
这些年我们犯过错
We've made some mistakes along the way.
最近就犯过一些
Some, very recently.
你带了任务来吗 长官
Are you here with a mission, sir?
没错
I am.
想让我"重出江湖"吗
Trying to get me back in the world?
想让你拯救世界
Trying to save it.
海德拉的秘密武器
HYDRA's secret weapon.
是霍华德·斯塔克找你的时候
Howard Stark fished that out of the ocean
从海里捞上来的
when he was looking for you.
他跟我们想到了一块儿
He thought what we think.
宇宙魔方可能是开发无限永续能源的关键
The Tesseract could be the key to unlimited sustainable energy.
这正是人类亟需的
That's something the world sorely needs.
被谁夺去了
Who took it from you?
他叫洛基
He's called Loki.
他算是远道而来了
He's not from around here.
如果你加入 还有很多情况需要了解
There's a lot we'll have to bring you up to speed on if you're in.
这世界比你记忆中
The world has gotten even stranger
更奇怪了
than you already know.
我现在已经见怪不怪了
At this point, I doubt anything would surprise me.
我赌10块说你错了
Ten bucks says you're wrong.
任务报告集
There's a debriefing packet
放在你公寓了
waiting for you back at your apartment.
关于宇宙魔方
Is there anything you can tell us about the Tesseract
有什么我们现在需要了解的吗
that we ought to know now?
你就不该把它捞上来
You should have left it in the ocean.
这边准备就绪 接下来看你的了
Good to go on this end. The rest is up to you.
你断开输电线了吗
You disconnected the transmission lines?
我们与电网断开了吗
Are we off the grid?
斯塔克大厦即将成为
Stark Tower is about to become a beacon
自给清洁能源的标志建筑
of self-sustaining clean energy.
如果方舟反应堆能够接替发电
Well, assuming the arc reactor takes over
并正常运行的话
and it actually works.
必须的
I assume.
点亮她吧
Light her up.
(斯塔克)
好看吗
How does it look?
像圣诞节 但更有我的范儿
Like Christmas, but with more me.
公众意识宣传得加大力度
We've got to go wider on the public awareness campaign.
你得在媒体上造势
You need to do some press.
明天我去华府
I'm in DC tomorrow,
我在为另三座大厦选址
I'm working on the zoning for the next three buildings.
小辣椒 别说了 享受这一刻
Pepper, you're killing me. The moment, remember?
忙里偷闲得几回嘛
Enjoy the moment.
你进来我才有的偷
Get in here and I will.
先生 神盾局的科尔森探员来电
Sir, Agent Coulson of S.H.I.E.L.D. Is on the line.
说我在外面
I'm not in.
严格说我的确在外面
I'm actually out.
先生 他坚持要找您
Sir, I'm afraid he's insisting.
有点骨气 贾维斯 我佳人有约
Grow a spine, Jarvis. I got a date.
能级稳定…吧
Levels are holding steady, I think.
必须的 我都亲自动手了
Of course they are. I was directly involved.
这正让我想到一个问题
Which brings me to my next question.
当天才的感觉如何
How does it feel to be a genius?
你真逗 我等俗人哪知道您的感受
Well, I really wouldn't know, now would I?
这叫什么话 这一切可都归功于你
What do you mean? All this came from you.
不 这一切归功于这个
No, all this came from that.
我的军功章也有你的一半嘛
Give yourself some credit. Please.
斯塔克大厦就是你的孩子
Stark Tower is your baby.
这个军功章12%是你的
Give yourself 12% of the credit.
才12%
12%?
好好讲讲可以说到15%
An argument can be made for 15.
我的孩子我只有12%的份
12%? My baby?
毕竟重活都是我干的
Well, I did do all the heavy lifting.
都不是打比方 重物都是我搬的
Literally, I lifted the heavy things.
再者 安保混乱的事
And, sorry, but the security snafu?
是你的错吧
That was on you.
- 我私人电梯的事 - 你是说我们的电梯吧
- My private elevator... - You mean our elevator?
挤了一堆一身臭汗的工人
...it was teeming with sweaty workmen.
你待会儿会为我分军功章的那一席话
I'm going to pay for that comment about percentages
而温柔地掐死我 是吧
in some subtle way later, aren't I?
不会很温柔
It's not going to be that subtle.
这样吧
I'll tell you what.
下一栋大厦会挂上"波茨"的大名
The next building is gonna say "Potts" On the tower.
挂在租契上吧
On the lease.
打电话问问你妈能不能留下来过夜
Call your mom. Can you bunk over?
先生 您的电话
Sir, the telephone.
我的规程被人改写了
I'm afraid my protocols are being overridden.
斯塔克 我有急事
Mr Stark, we need to talk.
我是托尼·斯塔克的活体假人
You have reached the life model decoy of Tony Stark.
- 请留言 - 是急事
- Please leave a message. - This is urgent.
那就说快点
Then leave it urgently.
安全漏洞 你的错
Security breach. It's on you.
- 斯塔克先生 - 菲尔 快进来
- Mr Stark. - Phil! Come in.
叫这么亲热干嘛
"Phil"?
我不能久留
I can't stay.
他名叫"探员"啊
His first name is "Agent."
进来吧 我们正在庆祝
Come on in. We're celebrating.
所以他不能久留
Which is why he can't stay.
你得看完这些资料 越快越好
We need you to look this over as soon as possible.
我不喜欢别人递给我东西
I don't like being handed things.
没事 我就喜欢别人递给我东西
That's fine, because I love to be handed things.
咱们换换吧
So, let's trade.
谢谢
Thank you.
正式咨询时间为每隔一周的周四8点到17点
Official consulting hours are between 8 and 5 every other Thursday.
这不是咨询
This isn't a consultation.
是关于复仇者联盟吗
Is this about the Avengers?
我对那个可一无所知
Which I know nothing about.
复仇者计划不是被弃了吗
The Avengers Initiative was scrapped, I thought.
再说我都不够格
And I didn't even qualify.
这我也不知情
I didn't know that either.
真的 人家嫌我反覆无常 自我为中心
Apparently I'm volatile, self-obsessed,
没有团队精神
don't play well with others.
这我还真知道
That I did know.
我们现在管不了性格如何了
This isn't about personality profiles any more.
随便了 波茨小姐 能过来一下吗
Whatever. Ms Potts, got a second?
稍等
Half a mo.
我以为我们俩能浪漫一会儿呢
You know, I thought we were having a moment.
我只能享受12%的浪漫
I was having 12% of a moment.
好像不是闹着玩的 菲尔似乎余惊未消
This seems serious. Phil's pretty shaken.
你怎么知道 你干嘛喊他菲尔
How would you know if it's... Why is he "Phil"?
这都是什么啊
What is all this?
这是
This is
自己瞧吧
this.
我今晚就飞去华府
I'm going to take the jet to DC tonight.
明天吧
Tomorrow.
你有资料要看 而且不少
You have homework. You have a lot of homework.
要是没有呢
Well, what if I didn't?
- 没有 - 是啊
- If you didn't? - Yeah.
你是说等你看完了
You mean when you've finished?
那…
Well, then...
说定了 旅途顺利
Square deal. Fly safe.
好好看
Work hard.
你路过拉加迪亚机场吗
So, any chance you're driving by LaGuardia?
- 我捎你一程吧 - 太好了
- I can drop you. - Fantastic.
跟我说说那个大提琴手
I want to hear about the cellist.
你们还在约会吗
Is that still a thing?
她回波特兰了
She moved back to Portland.
什么
What? Boo!
我们离总部还有约四十分钟航程 长官
We're about 40 minutes out from home base, sir.
班纳博士想复制用在我身上的血清吗
So, this Dr Banner was trying to replicate the serum they used on me?
很多人都试过
A lot of people were.
你是史上首个超级英雄
You were the world's first superhero.
班纳以为伽马射线可能是破解
Banner thought gamma radiation might hold the key
厄斯金原始配方的关键
to unlocking Erskine's original formula.
可惜事与愿违
Didn't really go his way, did it?
是啊
Not so much.
不过他正常的时候
When he's not that thing, though,
就像史蒂芬·霍金
the guy's like a Stephen Hawking.
是个很天才的人
He's like a smart person.
我得说
I gotta say,
能正式跟你见面是我的荣幸
it's an honour to meet you officially.
我之前其实见过你
I've sort of met you. I mean,
你昏睡时我去看过你
I watched you while you were sleeping.
我是说 你在冰里
I mean, I was present
昏迷不醒时 我也在
while you were unconscious from the ice.
说真的 这真是…你能加入
You know, it's really just a huge honour
真是莫大的荣幸
to have you on board this...
希望我能胜任
I hope I'm the man for the job.
肯定胜任 毫无疑问
Oh, you are. Absolutely.
我们对你的制服做了些修改
We made some modifications to the uniform.
我还提出了设计意见
I had a little design input.
我的制服
The uniform?
星条的样式不会…
Aren't the stars and stripes a little
太过时了吗
old-fashioned?
考虑到眼下的局势
With everything that's happening
和即将到来的恶战
and the things that are about to come to light,
人们或许正需要点过去的精神
people might just need a little old-fashioned.
齐塔瑞人越来越耐不住了
The Chitauri grow restless.
叫他们严阵以待
Let them gird themselves.
我将领导他们发动一场光荣的战役
I will lead them in the glorious battle.
战役
Battle?
就对付地球上羸弱的势力吗
Against the meagre might of Earth?
光荣之至 且速战速决
Glorious, not lengthy.
前提是你的大军如你说的那般所向披靡
If your force is as formidable as you claim.
你竟敢质疑我们
You question us?
质疑他
You question him,
别忘了是他把权杖交给了你
he who put the sceptre in your hand?
还传授你远古知识 给你新的使命
Who gave you ancient knowledge and new purpose
虽然你遭到流放 一败涂地
when you were cast out, defeated?
我可是阿斯加德之王
I was a king!
王位本该属于我
The rightful king of Asgard,
无奈遭人背叛
betrayed.
你这是器小志近
Your ambition is little
满心幼稚的念想
and born of childish need.
而我们则放眼地球之外
We look beyond the Earth
那些将被宇宙魔方开启的更广博的世界
to the greater worlds the Tesseract will unveil.
别忘了魔方还在我这儿
You don't have the Tesseract yet.
我没有威胁你的意思
I don't threaten.
但只要传送门尚未打开
But until I open the doors,
你的军队还非由我统领
until your force is mine to command,
你也只是空谈
you are but words.
阿斯加德人 你去发动战争吧
You will have your war, Asgardian.
可如果你战败
If you fail,
如果宇宙魔方落入他人之手
if the Tesseract is kept from us,
无论你躲到什么地方
there will be no realm, no barren moon,
我们也会把你找出来
no crevice where he cannot find you.
你自以为了解痛苦的滋味吗
You think you know pain?
他给你的折磨 会让你渴望痛苦
He will make you long for something sweet as pain.
去拿队长的行头
Stow the captain's gear.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
罗曼诺夫探员 这位是罗杰斯队长
Agent Romanoff, Captain Rogers.
- 女士 你好 - 你好
- Ma'am. - Hi.
舰桥那边找你
They need you on the bridge.
他们开始面部识别追踪了
They're starting the face-trace.
待会见
See you there.
在冰层中找到你的事引起了不小的轰动
It was quite the buzz around here, finding you in the ice.
我以为科尔森会乐晕呢
I thought Coulson was gonna swoon.
他求你给他的美国队长收藏卡签名了吗
Did he ask you to sign his Captain America trading cards yet?
收藏卡
Trading cards?
绝版珍藏呢 他很以为傲
They're vintage. He's very proud.
班纳博士
Dr Banner.
你好
Yeah, hi.
我听说你要来
They told me you would be coming.
我听说你能找到魔方
Word is, you can find the Cube.
你没听到别的吗
Is that the only word on me?
别的我都当耳边风了
Only word I care about.
你一定觉得这一切很奇怪吧
It must be strange for you, all of this.
老实说 我倒有种久违之感
Well, this is actually kind of familiar.
二位还是快进去吧
Gentlemen, you might want to step inside in a minute.
这里待会就难以呼吸了
It's going to get a little hard to breathe.
空勤人员 清空甲板
Flight crew, secure the deck.
这是潜艇吗
Is this a submarine?
不是吧
Really?
要我待在水下密闭加压的金属罐里吗
They want me in a submerged, pressurised, metal container?
不 这个更糟
No, no, this is much worse.
盘旋动力检查完毕 位置稳定
Hover power check complete. Position cyclic.
动力增大至8%
Increase collective to 8.0%.
准备全速起航
Preparing for maximum performance takeoff.
将输出升到最高
Increase output to capacity.
全速模式
Power plant performing at capacity.
准备就绪
We are clear.
引擎全部开启
All engines operating.
施行神盾局193.6号紧急协议
S.H.I.E.L.D. Emergency Protocol 193.6 in effect.
- 航母已达预定高度 长官 - 很好
- We are at level, sir. - Good.
我们消失吧
Let's vanish.
开启反光板
Engage retro-reflection panels.
反光板已开启
Reflection panels engaged.
各位好
Gentlemen.
谢谢你能来 博士
Doctor, thank you for coming.
谢谢你们没动粗
Thanks for asking nicely.
我要在这里待多长久
So, how long am I staying?
我们一拿到宇宙魔方
Once we get our hands on the Tesseract,
就会让你走
you're in the wind.
你们进展如何
Where are you with that?
我们在扫描全球所有
We're sweeping every wirelessly accessible
可无线读取的摄像头
camera on the planet.
手机 笔记本
Cell phones, laptops...
只要连接了卫星 就是我们的眼线
If it's connected to a satellite, it's eyes and ears for us.
就这么找还是来不及
That's still not gonna find them in time.
你们得缩小范围
You have to narrow your field.
你能调用多少台光谱仪
How many spectrometers do you have access to?
要多少有多少
How many are there?
联系所有你找得到的实验室
Call every lab you know.
叫他们把光谱仪放在房顶
Tell them to put the spectrometers on the roof
校准搜索伽马射线
and calibrate them for gamma rays.
我会根据聚类识别草拟出跟踪算法
I'll rough out a tracking algorithm, basic cluster recognition.
起码能排除几个区域
At least we could rule out a few places.
能给我找个干活的地方吗
Do you have somewhere for me to work?
罗曼诺夫探员
Agent Romanoff,
麻烦你带班纳博士去他的实验室
could you show Dr. Banner to his laboratory, please?
那里一应俱全 包您满意 博士
You're gonna love it, Doc. We got all the toys.
放到那边去
Put it over there.
这些人你从哪找来的
Where did you find all these people?
神盾局从不缺敌人 博士
S.H.I.E.L.D. has no shortage of enemies, Doctor.
你要的是这个吗
Is this the stuff you need?
(海因里希·赛弗博士)
铱 就是它
Yeah, iridium.
陨石里有 能形成反质子
It's found in meteorites. It forms anti-protons.
这东西很难找
It's very hard to get hold of.
要是神盾局知道你需要它就更难找了
Especially if S.H.I.E.L.D. knows you need it.
这我都没想到
Well, I didn't know.
宇宙魔方让我看到了太多
The Tesseract has shown me so much.
已经超越了知识 而是真理
It's more than knowledge. It's truth.
我懂
I know.
巴顿探员 它给你看了什么
What did it show you, Agent Barton?
我下个目标
My next target.
你需要什么
Tell me what you need.
一场混乱 分散注意
I need a distraction.
和一颗眼珠
And an eyeball.
那个…太麻烦就算了
I mean, if it's not too much trouble.
哪里 不麻烦
No, no. It's fine.
是绝版套牌
It's a vintage set.
我找了几年才集齐
It took me a couple of years to collect them all.
还很新呢
Near mint.
边角有点泛黄 但…
Slight foxing around the edges, but...
有发现 面部特征67%吻合
We got a hit. A 67% match.
等等 交叉比对显示79%吻合
Wait. Cross match, 79%.
在哪
Location?
德国斯图加特 库宁大街28号
Stuttgart, Germany. 28, Canning Strasse.
他就没有躲起来的意思
He's not exactly hiding.
队长
Captain,
上
you're up.
(视网膜扫描 身份识别 海因里希·赛弗博士 开锁)
给我下跪
Kneel before me.
聋了吗
I said
下跪
kneel!
这样多好
Is not this simpler?
回归你们本来的状态
Is this not your natural state?
人之初 性本奴
It's the unspoken truth of humanity,
只是没人说穿罢了
that you crave subjugation.
自由看似光鲜 诱惑着你们
The bright lure of freedom
去疯抢权力 去寻求个性
diminishes your life's joy in a mad scramble for power,
其实夺去了人生的乐趣
for identity.
你们天生就该受人统治
You were made to be ruled.
到头来
In the end,
你们总会俯首称臣
you will always kneel.
不会向你这样的人称臣
Not to men like you.
你再找不出我这样的人了
There are no men like me.
你这样的疯子层出不穷
There are always men like you.
各位 瞧瞧这个老头
Look to your elder, people.
我就用他 杀一儆百
Let him be an example.
知道吗 我上次来德国时
You know, the last time I was in Germany,
也遇到一个将别人踩在脚下的人
and saw a man standing above everybody else,
我们闹掰了
we ended up disagreeing.
是美国大兵啊
The soldier.
被时间甩在后面的人
The man out of time.
至少我还有时间 你则大限将至
I'm not the one who's out of time.
洛基 放下武器 马上投降
Loki, drop the weapon and stand down.
下跪
Kneel.
休想
Not today!
到处都是他的分身
The guy's all over the place.
罗曼诺夫探员 想我没
Agent Romanoff. You miss me?
(广播系统被改写)
出招啊 小鹿斑比
Make your move, Reindeer Games.
这才乖
Good move.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark.
队长
Captain.
他开口了吗
Is he saying anything?
一言未发
Not a word.
带回来再说 时间不多了
Just get him here. We're low on time.
我有不好的感觉
I don't like it.
摇滚明星乖乖投降有什么不好的
What? Rock of Ages giving up so easily?
他可是抵抗了好一番
I don't remember it being that easy.
这家伙挺能打的
This guy packs a wallop.
不管怎样 你一把年纪 身手还蛮敏捷的
Still, you are pretty spry for an older fellow.
你做什么锻炼 普拉提吗
What's your thing, Pilates?
你说什么
What?
跟健美操差不多
It's like calisthenics.
有些事你可能不知道
You might have missed a couple of things
毕竟做了那么久的美队棒棒冰
doing time as a Capsicle.
弗瑞没说他也找你了
Fury didn't tell me he was calling you in.
是啊 弗瑞没说的事多了
Yeah, there's a lot of things Fury doesn't tell you.
这怎么打起闪了
Where's this coming from?
干嘛 打个闪你也怕
What's the matter? Are you scared of a little lightning?
我是不喜欢紧随闪电而来的家伙
I'm not overly fond of what follows.
你要干嘛
What are you doing?
又来个添乱的
And now there's that guy.
他也是阿斯加德的吗
Another Asgardian?
- 你说他是我们这边的吗 - 无所谓
- That guy's a friendly? - Doesn't matter.
他要是放了洛基或杀了他
If he frees Loki or kills him,
宇宙魔方都找不回来了
the Tesseract's lost.
斯塔克 我们需要出击计划
Stark, we need a plan of attack!
我有计划 出击
I have a plan. Attack.
别去搅这浑水了 队长
I'd sit this one out, Cap.
这我做不到
I don't see how I can.
他们都是传说啊 差不多就是神
These guys come from legend. They're basically gods.
神只有上帝一个 女士
There's only one God, ma'am.
而且他肯定不会穿成那样
And I'm pretty sure he doesn't dress like that.
宇宙魔方在哪
Where is the Tesseract?
我也想你了
I missed you, too.
我像是有心情跟你闹着玩吗
Do I look to be in a gaming mood?
你该谢我才是
You should thank me.
彩虹桥已毁 众神之父聚集了多少暗能
With the Bifrost gone, how much dark energy did the Allfather have
才将你传送到
to muster to conjure you here
你的宝贝地球来
to your precious Earth?
我以为你死了
I thought you dead.
你为我哀悼了吗
Did you mourn?
我们都哀悼了 我们的父王
We all did. Our father...
是你的父王
Your father.
他把我的身世告诉你了吧
He did tell you my true parentage, did he not?
我们从小一起长大
We were raised together.
一起玩 一起打
We played together, we fought together.
你不记得了吗
Do you remember none of that?
我只记得一道阴影
I remember a shadow.
你的威武投下的阴影一直笼罩着我
Living in the shade of your greatness.
我只记得你将我扔下深渊
I remember you tossing me into an abyss.
我可是国王 王位本该是我的
I, who was, and should be, king!
那你就祸害我珍视的世界
So you take the world I love as a recompense
来补偿你臆想出的轻慢
for your imagined slights?
没门 我会保护地球 洛基
No. The Earth is under my protection, Loki.
瞧你保护得多好
And you're doing a marvellous job with that.
人类成群地相互残杀
The humans slaughter each other in droves
你却傻在一边干着急
while you idly fret.
我想统治他们 这有何不可
I mean to rule them, as why should I not?
你自以为高他们一等吗
You think yourself above them?
当然
Well, yes.
那你就没领会统治的真谛 弟弟
Then you miss the truth of ruling, brother.
你不适合做国王
A throne would suit you ill.
我见过你所不知的世界
I've seen worlds you've never known about!
奥丁之子 流放的日子里 我长了见识
I have grown, Odinson, in my exile.
我见识过宇宙魔方的真正力量
I have seen the true power of the Tesseract,
等我控制它时
and when I wield it...
是谁向你展示了它的力量
Who showed you this power?
你这自封之王听命于谁
Who controls the would-be king?
- 我本就是国王 - 在这儿不是
- I am a king! - Not here!
交出宇宙魔方
You give up the Tesseract!
放下这恶毒的野心吧
You give up this poisonous dream!
跟哥回家
You come home.
魔方不在我手上
I don't have it.
没有它你不能带我回家
You need the Cube to bring me home.
但我把它转移了 我也不知移到了哪
But I've sent it off, I know not where.
给哥听着 弟弟
You listen well, brother.
小弟听着呢
I'm listening.
再动我要你好看
Do not touch me again.
那你也别动我的东西
Then don't take my stuff.
你别这么不知深浅
You have no idea what you're dealing with.
这是莎翁戏剧的公园公演吗
Shakespeare in the Park?
"尔取帘为披风 汝母安知"（莎翁戏剧词）
"Doth Mother know you wear-eth her drapes?"
这事你管不了 铁人
This is beyond you, metal man.
洛基会依阿斯加德的法律受到制裁
Loki will face Asgardian justice.
只要他交出魔方 你就可以带他回家 否则
He gives up the Cube, he's all yours. Until then,
好狗不挡道
stay out of the way.
你个观光客
Tourist.
你狠
Okay.
电能达到400%
Power at 400% capacity.
这个可以有
How about that?
你俩够了
That's enough.
我不知道你想干嘛
Now, I don't know what you plan on doing here.
我是来粉碎洛基的阴谋
I've come here to put an end to Loki's schemes.
用行动说话 把锤子放下
Then prove it. Put that hammer down.
不行
Yeah... No.
坏主意 他爱死他的锤子了
Bad call. He loves his hammer.
你要我放下锤子
You want me to put the hammer down?
打够了没
Are we done, here?
丑话说前面
In case it's unclear,
试图逃跑
if you try to escape,
或者哪怕挠那玻璃一下
if you so much as scratch that glass,
你就会跟着这牢笼坠落九千米的高空
it's 30,000 feet straight down in a steel trap.
听懂了吗
You get how that works?
尔为蚂蚁 爷为靴子
Ant, boot.
这笼子真不赖
It's an impressive cage.
我猜不是为我造的吧
Not built, I think, for me.
是为比你还厉害的东西建的
Built for something a lot stronger than you.
有所耳闻
Oh, I've heard.
明明是愚蠢的野兽
A mindless beast.
却装作自己还是常人
Makes play he's still a man.
你这是多慌不择路
How desperate are you,
把这样的怪兽也当做救兵
that you call on such lost creatures to defend you?
慌不择路
How desperate am I?
你威胁说要向我的世界开战
You threaten my world with war.
你偷了你无法掌控的能量
You steal a force you can't hope to control.
嘴上说什么安宁 却以杀戮为乐
You talk about peace, and you kill because it's fun.
你已逼得我不择手段
You have made me very desperate.
而你会吃不了兜着走
You might not be glad that you did.
功败垂成让你痛苦万分吧
It burns you to have come so close.
拿到了宇宙魔方 拥有其能量
To have the Tesseract, to have power,
还是无限的能量
unlimited power.
你却用来做什么
And for what?
点一盏明灯 照亮全人类吗
A warm light for all mankind to share.
然后才领教到真正力量的厉害
And then to be reminded what real power is.
真正力量要是想看杂志了跟我说一声
Well, let me know if "Real power" wants a magazine or something.
真是越看越讨人喜欢的娃啊
He really grows on you, doesn't he?
洛基是在拖延时间
Loki's gonna drag this out.
托尔 他到底打的什么算盘
So, Thor, what's his play?
他有一支齐塔瑞人的大军
He has an army called the Chitauri.
谁都不知道他们的来头
They're not of Asgard, nor any world known.
他打算领着这支大军侵略你们
He means to lead them against your people.
他们会助他夺取地球
They will win him the Earth,
我猜 作为交换 他要交出宇宙魔方
in return, I suspect, for the Tesseract.
大军
An army
还是外太空的大军
from outer space.
那他还得建一个传送门啊
So, he's building another portal.
他掳走艾瑞克·塞尔维格就是为这个
That's what he needs Erik Selvig for.
塞尔维格
Selvig?
- 他是个天体物理学家 - 我们认识
- He's an astrophysicist. - He's a friend.
洛基不知怎么控制了他
Loki has him under some kind of spell,
还有我们一个探员
along with one of ours.
我想知道洛基怎么会甘愿束手就擒
I want to know why Loki let us take him.
他困在这儿又没法指挥大军
He's not leading an army from here.
我觉得我们不该一心想着洛基
I don't think we should be focusing on Loki.
这家伙就是个疯子
That guy's brain is a bag full of cats.
一眼就能看出来
You could smell crazy on him.
说话注意点
Have care how you speak.
洛基再怎么蛮横无理 也是我们阿斯加德的人
Loki is beyond reason, but he is of Asgard.
也是我弟弟
And he is my brother.
他两天内杀了八十人
He killed 80 people in two days.
他是领养的
He's adopted.
该往机械方面想
I think it's about the mechanics.
- 铱 他们为什么要窃取铱 - 铱可用作稳定剂
- Iridium... What do they need the iridium for? - It's a stabilising agent.
随便哪个周末
I'm just saying, pick a weekend.
我飞你去波特兰
I'll fly you to Portland.
得保持浓情蜜意
Keep love alive.
能防止传送门出现自我坍圮
It means the portal won't collapse on itself
就像之前在神盾局那样
like it did at S.H.I.E.L.D.
别记仇 大块头 你那两下真够劲
No hard feelings, Point Break. You've got a mean swing.
还能让洛基随心所欲地扩展传送门
Also, it means the portal can open as wide
并开放很长时间
and stay open as long, as Loki wants.
升起后桅 调转顶帆
Raise the mizzenmast. Jib the topsails.
那个人在玩小蜜蜂
That man is playing Galaga.
自以为别人看不到 但是我看到了
He thought we wouldn't notice, but we did.
弗瑞怎么能看到两边的屏幕
How does Fury even see these?
转身看
He turns.
听上去真累人
Sounds exhausting.
其他原材料
The rest of the raw materials,
巴顿探员都能轻松地弄到
Agent Barton can get his hands on pretty easily.
他只缺一个主部件 就是能源
The only major component he still needs is a power source
某种高密度能量
of high-energy density.
以激活魔方
Something to kick-start the Cube.
你什么时候对热核天体物理学这么有研究
When did you become an expert in thermonuclear astrophysics?
就昨晚
Last night.
资料集 塞尔维格的笔记
The packet, Selvig's notes,
那些萃取论的论文
the extraction theory papers.
你们都没看吗
Am I the only one who did the reading?
洛基需要什么特定的能源吗
Does Loki need any particular kind of power source?
他得将魔方加热到一亿多度
He would have to heat the Cube to 120-million Kelvin
才能超过库仑势垒
just to break through the Coulomb barrier.
除非 塞尔维格已经想出
Unless Selvig has figured out
稳定量子隧穿效应的方法
how to stabilise the quantum tunnelling effect.
他要是真想出来了
Well, if he could do that,
就能用任何一个反应堆完成重离子束聚变
he could achieve heavy ion fusion at any reactor on the planet.
终于有个说人话的了
Finally, someone who speaks English.
你管这叫人话
Is that what just happened?
幸会 班纳博士
It's good to meet you, Dr Banner.
你对反电子碰撞的研究真是无与伦比
Your work on antielectron collisions is unparalleled.
而且我觉得你失去控制
And I'm a huge fan of the way you lose control
就变身狂暴绿巨人的样子超赞
and turn into an enormous green rage-monster.
夸奖了
Thanks.
班纳博士此行只为追踪魔方
Dr Banner is only here to track the Cube.
我希望你能跟他一起找
I was hoping you might join him.
从他的权杖入手吧
I would start with that stick of his.
不管有没有魔力
It may be magical,
它的运作方式很像海德拉的武器
but it works an awful lot like a Hydra weapon.
海德拉我不了解 但权杖的确由魔方驱动
I don't know about that, but it is powered by the Cube.
我还想知道
And I would like to know
它是怎么把我见过的最机警的两个人
how Loki used it to turn two of the sharpest men I know
变成了洛基的飞猴
into his personal flying monkeys.
什么飞猴（飞猴出自《绿野仙踪》）
Monkeys? I do not understand.
这我知道
I do.
我知道这个典故
I understood that reference.
我们开工吧 博士
Shall we play, Doctor?
这边请
This way, sir.
伽马读数跟塞尔维格的宇宙魔方报告
The gamma readings are definitely consistent with
是相符的
Selvig's reports of the Tesseract.
但处理数据要耗时数周
But it's going to take weeks to process.
如果我们绕过他们的主机
If we bypass their mainframe
直接上连主集群
and direct route to the Homer cluster,
速度可达每秒六百万亿次浮点运算
we can clock this at around 600 teraflops.
我可就带了个牙刷
All I packed was a toothbrush.
你哪天该来斯塔克大厦玩
You know, you should come by Stark Tower sometime.
上数十层是研究开发部
Top ten floors, all R&D.
肯定对你胃口 简直是糖果乐园
You'd love it. It's Candy Land.
客气 不过我上次去纽约时
Thanks, but the last time I was in New York,
把哈莱姆区给砸了（哈莱姆是纽约黑人区 出自《无敌浩克》）
I kind of broke Harlem.
我保证给你零压力环境
Well, I promise a stress-free environment.
气氛缓和 绝不吓唬你
No tension, no surprises.
这都不变身
Nothing?
你有病啊
Are you nuts?
难说啊
Jury's out.
你还真能压得住火气啊
You really have got a lid on it, haven't you?
说说诀窍
What's your secret?
舒缓爵士乐 邦哥鼓 还是抽一大袋大麻
Mellow jazz, bongo drums, huge bag of weed?
你什么事都不当真吗
Is everything a joke to you?
好笑的不当真
Funny things are.
威胁航母上所有人的生命安全并不好笑
Threatening the safety of everyone on this ship isn't funny.
博士 别介意
No offence, Doc.
没事的
It's all right,
我要是挨点扎就爆发也不会来了
I wouldn't have come aboard if I couldn't handle pointy things.
别这么谨小慎微的 大个子
You're tip-toeing, big man.
你该放开点
You need to strut.
而你该专心解决问题 斯塔克先生
And you need to focus on the problem, Mr Stark.
你觉得我没有吗
Do you think I'm not?
弗瑞干嘛现在找我们来 之前干嘛去了
Why did Fury call us in? Why now? Why not before?
他对我们隐瞒了什么
What isn't he telling us?
信息不全 我就无法解答
I can't do the equation unless I have all the variables.
你说弗瑞有秘密
You think Fury's hiding something?
- 他可是间谍 - 队长啊 他可是谍中谍
- He's a spy. - Captain, he's "The" Spy.
他的秘密会下崽
His secrets have secrets.
博士也纠结这事呢 是不是
It's bugging him, too. Isn't it?
我只想完成手头的工作...
I just want to finish my work here, and...
有话直说
Doctor?
点亮明灯 照亮全人类
"A warm light for all mankind."
关于魔方 洛基挖苦弗瑞的那句话
Loki's jab at Fury about the Cube.
我也听到了
I heard it.
我认为他是说给你听的
I think that was meant for you.
就是巴顿没说 关于大厦的报道
Even if Barton didn't tell Loki about the tower,
也是铺天盖地
it was still all over the news.
斯塔克大厦
The Stark Tower?
就是纽约那座又大又丑的…建筑物
That big, ugly building in New York?
给大厦供能的方舟反应堆 是自给能源
It's powered by an arc reactor, a self-sustaining energy source.
大厦一年内都不需外部能源吧
That building will run itself for, what, a year?
还只是个雏型
It's just the prototype.
可以说我是当今清洁能源界的独秀
I'm kind of the only name in clean energy right now.
他就是这个意思
That's what he's getting at.
那神盾局怎么不把他
So, why didn't S.H.I.E.L.D.
招进宇宙魔方计划
Bring him in on the Tesseract project?
况且 他们当初
What are they doing in the energy business
干嘛要染指能源业
in the first place?
这的确值得调查一番 只等我的解密程序完成
I should probably look into that once my decryption programme
破解所有神盾局加密文件 我就去查
finishes breaking into all of S.H.I.E.L.D.'s secure files.
你说什么
I'm sorry. Did you say...
我一上舰桥贾维斯就开始运行破解程序了
Jarvis has been running it since I hit the bridge.
几小时后 我便能得知
In a few hours, I'll know
所有神盾局想隐瞒的不可告人的秘密
every dirty secret S.H.I.E.L.D. Has ever tried to hide.
来点蓝莓
Blueberry?
就你这样还不明白人家干嘛不想要你
Yet you're confused about why they didn't want you around.
情报部门还怕人窃取情报
An intelligence organisation that fears intelligence?
真是丢脸啊
Historically, not awesome.
我看洛基就是想搞得我们草木皆兵
I think Loki's trying to wind us up.
他可是想发动战争的人
This is a man who means to start a war
我们不专心御敌 他就会得逞
and if we don't stay focused, he'll succeed.
我们该服从命令听指挥
We have orders. We should follow them.
服从命令不是我的风格
Following's not really my style.
风格就是你的命根 是吗
And you're all about style, aren't you?
这屋里谁
Of the people in this room,
一身花里胡哨
which one is, A, wearing a spangly outfit,
却又一无是处
and, B, not of use?
史蒂夫 你真的不觉得有蹊跷吗
Steve, tell me none of this smells a little funky to you.
赶紧找魔方吧
Just find the Cube.
我爸竟对这家伙赞不绝口
That's the guy my dad never shut up about?
真该让他继续做冰棍儿
I'm wondering if they shouldn't have kept him on ice.
关于洛基他说得对
The guy's not wrong about Loki.
那瘟神的确胜我们一筹
He does have the jump on us.
洛基就是有套顶级装备
What he's got is an Acme dynamite kit.
早晚还得毁在那上面
It's going to blow up in his face.
到时候我就前排看戏
And I'm going to be there when it does.
那我就在家看报
Yeah. I'll read all about it.
或许你也会跟我们一起披挂上阵
Or you'll be suiting up with the rest of us.
我可没有铁甲护身
You see, I don't get a suit of armour.
就那么赤膊上阵 像个疯子
I'm exposed. Like a nerve.
完全是场灾难
It's a nightmare.
我身体里有一堆弹片
You know, I've got a cluster of shrapnel
时刻都在往我心脏里爬
trying every second to crawl its way into my heart.
被这个挡住了
This stops it.
就是这个小小的光环
This little circle of light,
如今它不仅是铁甲
it's part of me now,
已与我融为一体
not just armour.
是种可怕的特权
It's a terrible privilege.
- 可你控制得了它 - 那是我摸索出了方法
- But you can control it. - Because I learned how.
我们不一样
It's different.
你的"意外事故"我都听说了
Hey, I read all about your accident.
你受了那么强的伽玛辐射 死三回都够了
That much gamma exposure should have killed you.
你是说绿巨人…
So you're saying that the Hulk...
那个家伙救了我一命
The other guy saved my life?
好啊
That's nice.
这么想挺好 可他救我干嘛
It's a nice sentiment. Saved it for what?
或许答案不久就会揭晓
I guess we'll find out.
那个"答案"你未必喜欢
You may not enjoy that.
但你可能喜欢
And you just might.
(机密仓库)
洛基掳走了博士后
As soon as Loki took the doctor,
我们转移了简·福斯特
we moved Jane Foster.
特罗瑟姆（挪威城市）有座很好的天文台
They've got an excellent observatory in Troms?
昨天突然有人请她去做顾问
She was asked to consult there very suddenly yesterday.
酬金不菲 搭乘私人飞机 离这儿很远
Handsome fee, private plane, very remote.
她不会有事
She'll be safe.
谢谢
Thank you.
洛基抓走艾瑞克·塞尔维格绝非偶然
It's no accident, Loki taking Erik Selvig.
我怕洛基折腾够了就会害死他
I dread what he plans for him once he's done.
艾瑞克是个好人
Erik is a good man.
他常说起你
He talks about you a lot.
你改变了他的生活
You changed his life.
你改变了这个世界
You changed everything around here.
还是以前那样好些
They were better as they were.
在阿斯加德 我们自视高人一等
We pretend on Asgard that we're more advanced
却像俾施泰姆一样来这儿胡作非为
but we come here, battling like bilge snipe.
- 像什么 - 俾施泰姆
- Like what? - Bilge snipe.
就是那种有鳞甲和大角的巨兽
You know, huge, scaly, big antlers.
- 地球上没有吗 - 貌似没有
- You don't have those? - I don't think so.
那东西很可恶
Well, they are repulsive.
途经之地万物尽毁
And they trample everything in their path.
我第一次来地球时 洛基的盛怒也尾随而至
When I first came to Earth, Loki's rage followed me here,
人类为此遭受劫难
and your people paid the price.
现在历史又重演
And now, again.
年轻时我好战黩武
In my youth, I courted war.
战斗还没打响呢
War hasn't started yet.
你能从洛基口中逼问出
You think you could make Loki tell us
魔方的下落吗
where the Tesseract is?
难说 洛基的心思深不可测
I do not know. Loki's mind is far afield.
他不仅渴望权力 还想报复我
It's not just power he craves, it's vengeance, upon me.
任何折磨都难以撼动他的野心
There's no pain would prise his need from him.
很多人都自诩是不倒泰山
A lot of guys think that
只是狂风刮得不够烈
until the pain starts.
你要我做什么
What are you asking me to do?
我要问你 你愿意做什么
I'm asking, what are you prepared to do?
洛基现在是阶下囚
Loki is a prisoner.
那我怎么会觉得
Then why do I feel like
只有他想待在这艘航母上呢
he's the only person on this boat that wants to be here?
能偷偷接近我的人可不多
There's not many people who can sneak up on me.
可你料定我会来
But you figured I'd come.
有点早了
After.
我以为等弗瑞想不出折磨我的新招了
After whatever tortures Fury can concoct,
你才会粉墨登场 假意友好 来安抚我
you would appear as a friend, as a balm.
我就会全盘招供了
And I would cooperate.
我想知道你把巴顿探员怎么了
I want to know what you've done to Agent Barton.
我开拓了他的心智
I would say I've expanded his mind.
等你赢了
And once you've won,
等你称了王 称了霸
once you're king of the mountain,
他的心智会怎样
what happens to his mind?
你问这些是出于爱吗 罗曼诺夫探员
Is this love, Agent Romanoff?
小孩子才谈情说爱 我是欠他人情
Love is for children. I owe him a debt.
说来听听
Tell me.
进神盾局前 我…
Before I worked for S.H.I.E.L. D... I...
我早已声名远扬
Well, I made a name for myself.
我会一些特定的技能
I have a very specific skill set.
但我黑白不分 滥杀无辜
I didn't care who I used it for, or on.
于是被神盾局盯上了
I got on S.H.I.E.L.D.'s radar in a bad way.
他们派巴顿探员来杀我
Agent Barton was sent to kill me.
但他改了主意
He made a different call.
要是我保证放他一条生路 你怎么回报我
And what will you do if I vow to spare him?
我不会放了你
Not let you out.
我知道 可这多有趣
No, but I like this.
整个世界都危在旦夕 你却为一个人讨价还价
Your world in the balance, and you bargain for one man.
政权的颠覆司空见惯
Regimes fall every day.
我不想为这个伤心难过 我是俄国人
I tend not to weep over that. I'm Russian.
曾经是
Or I was.
那你现在又是什么人
And what are you now?
这事很简单
It's really not that complicated.
我欠了债 就要偿还
I got red in my ledger, I'd like to wipe it out.
还债
Can you?
那么多债 你还得清吗
Can you wipe out that much red?
德科夫之女
Dreykov's daughter,
圣保罗
St Paulo,
医院的火灾
the hospital fire?
巴顿都告诉我了
Barton told me everything.
你的血债罄竹难书
Your ledger is dripping. It's gushing red
你以为救一个比你强不到哪去的人
and you think saving a man no more virtuous than yourself
就能改变什么吗
will change anything?
这就是妇人之仁
This is the basest sentimentality.
像个孩子请求宽恕 真可悲
This is a child at prayer.
真可悲
Pathetic!
你为骗子撒谎
You lie and kill
给杀手当屠刀
in the service of liars and killers.
(发现病毒 非法入侵)
你自命不凡 装作是在以自己的准则行事
You pretend to be separate, to have your own code,
想以此为你所犯罪行的借口
something that makes up for the horrors.
但那是你的一部分了
But they are part of you.
永远无法抹去
And they will never go away.
我会留着巴顿 好逼他杀了你
I won't touch Barton, not until I make him kill you.
用他知道你最怕的手段
Slowly, intimately,
一点点亲手宰了你
in every way he knows you fear.
这时我就唤醒他 让他有时间欣赏自己的杰作
And then he'll wake just long enough to see his good work
等他痛苦哀嚎之时 我再劈开他的头
and when he screams, I'll split his skull.
这是我还的价 你这哭哭啼啼的婊子
This is my bargain, you mewling quim.
你这个禽兽
You're a monster.
不
Oh, no.
你带来的那位才叫兽
You brought the monster.
班纳
So, Banner.
那就是你的计划
That's your play.
什么
What?
洛基想诱绿巨人变身
Loki means to unleash the Hulk.
别让班纳出实验室 我马上到
Keep Banner in the lab. I'm on my way.
把托尔也找去
Send Thor as well.
谢谢合作
Thank you for your cooperation.
你在干什么 斯塔克先生
What are you doing, Mr Stark?
这话我还想问你呢
Kind of been wondering the same thing about you.
你该去搜寻宇宙魔方的下落
You're supposed to be locating the Tesseract.
在搜 搜索模型已锁定
We are. The model's locked
正在扫描搜索信号
and we're sweeping for the signature now.
一有结果
When we get a hit,
能把范围缩小至八百米内
we'll have the location within half a mile.
然后你就能拿回魔方 稍安毋躁
Yeah, then you get your Cube back. No muss, no fuss.
第二阶段是什么
What is "Phase 2"?
第二阶段是神盾局将魔方用于制造武器
Phase 2 is S.H.I.E.L.D. Uses the Cube to make weapons.
抱歉 我等不起计算机了
Sorry, computer was moving a little slow for me.
罗杰斯 我们搜集所有与魔方相关的东西
Rogers, we gathered everything related to the Tesseract.
这并不意味着我们…
This does not mean that we're making...
打断一下 尼克
I'm sorry, Nick.
你还想怎么编
What were you lying?
我错了 局长
I was wrong, Director.
世界还是那个老样子
The world hasn't changed a bit.
这事你知情吗
Did you know about this?
你是不是离开这里 博士
You want to think about removing yourself from this environment, Doctor?
我在加尔各答（印度城市）时离这儿远着呢
I was in Calcutta. I was pretty well removed.
洛基想摆布你
Loki is manipulating you.
你就不是吗
And you've been doing what, exactly?
你肯来不是被我的秋波打动
You didn't come here because I bat my eyelashes at you.
对 我也不会因为你突然觉得不安就走
Yes, and I'm not leaving because suddenly you get a little twitchy.
解释一下神盾局干嘛
I'd like to know why S.H.I.E.L.D.
要用宇宙魔方开发大规模杀伤性武器
Is using the Tesseract to build weapons of mass destruction.
因为他
Because of him.
关我什么事
Me?
去年 一个外星来客光临地球
Last year, Earth had a visitor from another planet
两虎相争 结果踏平了一座小镇
who had a grudge match that levelled a small town.
我们不仅得知了宇宙中其他生命的存在
We learned that not only are we not alone
还发现我们的武力远远落后于他们
but we are hopelessly, hilariously, outgunned.
我的人民只想与地球和平相处
My people want nothing but peace with your planet.
可你们不是唯一的外星生命吧
But you're not the only people out there, are you?
还有别的生物对我们构成威胁
And you're not the only threat.
宇宙到处是无可匹敌的强手
The world's filling up with people who can't be matched,
谁都控制不了他们
that can't be controlled.
你想像控制魔方那样控制他们
Like you controlled the Cube?
正因为你们用宇宙魔方制武器
Your work with the Tesseract
才招来了洛基和他的同伙
is what drew Loki to it, and his allies.
你这是给其他文明发出了信号
It is a signal to all the realms
宣告地球已准备好展开高级战争
that the Earth is ready for a higher form of war.
高级
A higher form?
还不是你逼的
You forced our hand.
我们总得想个办法
We had to come up with something.
于是想到了"核威慑"
A nuclear deterrent.
这总能平息事态
Because that always calms everything right down.
斯塔克 别忘了你的发家史
Remind me again how you made your fortune, Stark.
要是斯塔克还在造军火 肯定早就…
I'm sure if he still made weapons, Stark would be neck-deep...
等等 干嘛 这怎么冲我来了
Hold on. How is this now about me?
怎么 你不总是焦点吗
I'm sorry, isn't everything?
没想到人类这么野蛮
I thought humans were more evolved than this.
喂喂 人类跑去炸你家了吗
Excuse me, did we come to your planet and blow stuff up?
你居然如此不信任你们的守护者
You treat your champions with such mistrust.
你们怎么这么幼稚
Are you boys really that naive?
神盾局监视所有潜在威胁
S.H.I.E.L.D. monitors potential threats.
美国队长也是威胁
Captain America's on threat watch?
我们都是
We all are.
你也上黑名单了
Wait, you're on that list?
你跟愤怒的蜜蜂（游戏名）谁更靠前
Are you above or below angry bees?
史塔克 你再犯贫
Stark, so help me God, if you make one more wisecrack...
这是口头威胁啊 我好怕
Threat! Verbal threat. I feel threatened.
- 放尊重点 - 尊重什么
- Show some respect. - Respect what?
66B号运输机 请上报确认口令
Transport Six-Six-Bravo, please relay confirm codes.
系统里有你的资料 但没有航行记录
I've got you on the computer, but not on the day log.
请上报运输货物 完毕
What is your haul? Over.
武器弹药 完毕
Arms and ammunition. Over.
你嘴上说要控制 却惟恐天下不乱
You speak of control, yet you court chaos.
他就这作风 不是吗
That's his M.O., isn't it?
我们算哪门子团队
I mean, what are we, a team?
不 把我们搞在一起只会引发混乱
No, we're a chemical mixture that makes chaos.
我们…就是定时炸弹
We're a time bomb.
你别起哄
You need to step away.
干嘛不让他发发火 泄泄气
Why shouldn't the guy let off a little steam?
你明知故问 别捣乱
You know damn well why. Back off!
我想看你有没有本事逼我
I'm starting to want you to make me.
你厉害 穿着铁甲充大侠
Yeah. Big man in a suit of armour.
脱下铁甲 你还剩什么
Take that off, what are you?
天才 大款 花心萝卜 慈善家
Genius, billionaire, playboy, philanthropist.
我认识很多平凡的人 却胜你十倍
I know guys with none of that worth ten of you.
我看你的资料了
I've seen the footage.
你就只在乎你自己
The only thing you really fight for is yourself.
你不是那种会做出牺牲的人
You're not the guy to make the sacrifice play,
匐在铁丝网上让战友爬过去
to lay down on a wire and let the other guy crawl over you.
要是我就剪断铁丝网
I think I would just cut the wire.
总有鬼主意
Always a way out.
你也许不算是威胁
You may not be a threat
但你也别再扮英雄了
but you better stop pretending to be a hero.
你那样的英雄吗
A hero? Like you?
你就是个实验产物 罗杰斯
You're a laboratory experiment, Rogers.
从一瓶血清里获得了特殊能力
Everything special about you came out of a bottle.
穿上铁甲 我们大战几个回合
Put on the suit. Let's go a few rounds.
你们真小 小肚鸡肠
You people are so petty and tiny.
这就是我们的团队
Yeah, this is a team.
罗曼诺夫探员 请你
Agent Romanoff, would you escort
护送班纳博士回他的...
Dr Banner back to his...
哪儿 你把我房间租出去了
Where? You rented my room.
那个隔间只是…
The cell was just in case...
为万一你要杀我准备的
In case you needed to kill me.
可你杀不了 我试过 所以我知道
But you can't. I know, I tried.
我一度心灰意冷 觉得这种日子没有尽头
I got low. I didn't see an end.
就想吞枪自杀 那个家伙却把子弹吐了出来
So, I put a bullet in my mouth, and the other guy spit it out.
我只好活下去
So I moved on.
一心行医济世 本来好端端的
I focused on helping other people. I was good.
却被你拉来跟这些怪胎为伍
Until you dragged me back into this freak show
危及所有人的安全
and put everyone here at risk.
你不是问我有什么绝招吗 罗曼诺夫探员
You want to know my secret, Agent Romanoff?
我是怎么保持冷静的
You want to know how I stay calm?
班纳博士
Dr Banner,
放下权杖
put down the sceptre.
(能量信号吻合度95%)
找到了
Got it.
抱歉了 孩子们
Sorry, kids,
没机会看我亮绝活儿了
you don't get to see my party trick after all.
宇宙魔方找到了
You located the Tesseract?
我能最快赶过去
I could get there fastest.
宇宙魔方是阿斯加德的 人类消受不起
The Tesseract belongs on Asgard. No human is a match for it.
- 你不能自己去 - 有本事你就拦我啊
- You're not going alone. - You're gonna stop me?
穿上铁甲 看谁厉害
Put on the suit, let's find out.
打老年人我毫无压力
I'm not afraid to hit an old man.
去穿铁甲
Put on the suit.
(能量信号吻合度99%)
(能量信号吻合度100%)
不好
Oh, my God.
乖 去穿铁甲
Put on the suit.
好嘞
Yeah.
全体人员就位
All hands to stations.
- 希尔 - 航母外部爆炸
- Hill! - External detonation.
三号引擎停机
Number three engine is down.
我们受袭了
We've been hit.
- 能修好吗 - 3号引擎失火
- Can they get it running? - Fire in engine three!
什么情况
Talk to me.
涡轮机看来没大碍
Turbine looks mostly intact
但飞行状态下
but it's impossible to get out there to make repairs
无法进入故障区维修
while we're in the air.
再停一个引擎我们就飞不起来了
If we lose one more engine we won't be.
得找人出去修引擎
Somebody's got to get outside and patch that engine.
- 斯塔克 听到没 - 这就去
- Stark, you copy that? - I'm on it.
科尔森 启动关押区防御性封锁
Coulson, initiate defensive lockdown in the detention section,
然后去军械库
then get to the armoury.
罗曼诺夫
Romanoff?
我们没事
We're okay.
你没事吧
We're okay, right?
- 别让引擎启动 - 遵命
- Keep that engine down! - Yes, sir.
去关押层 等摄像头关闭
Detention, wait for cameras to go dark.
- 收到 - 跟紧
- Got it. - Stay close.
走 去4层
Let's go, Level 4.
三号引擎 去那儿见
Engine three. I'll meet you there.
博士
Doctor?
布鲁斯
Bruce?
撑住啊 洛基就等着你失控呢
You got to fight it. This is just what Loki wants.
不会有事的 听我说
We're going to be okay. Listen to me.
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
不会有事 听到了吗
We're going to be okay. All right?
我以生命起誓 会带你出去
I swear on my life I will get you out of this.
你不用蹚这浑水 再也不…
You will walk away and never ever...
你的生命
Your life?
布鲁斯
Bruce.
调转航母 航向180 向南行进
Bring the carrier about to a 1-8-0, heading south!
- 开上海域 - 我们在仪表飞行
- Take us to the water! - We're flying blind.
引擎故障后 导航系统重置了
Navigation's recalibrating after the engine failure.
天上有太阳没
Is the sun coming up?
- 是的 长官 - 保持太阳在航母左侧行进
- Yes, sir. - Then put it on the left.
上海域
Get us over water.
再有涡轮熄火就要坠毁了
One more turbine goes down, and we drop.
谢谢
Thanks.
斯塔克
Stark!
斯塔克 我来了
Stark, I'm here!
很好
Good.
看看是什么情况
Let's see what we've got.
得先把超导冷却系统接好
I got to get this superconducting coolant system back online
才能进入转子
before I can access the rotors,
清理残骸
work on dislodging the debris.
你去引擎控制面板那里
I need you to get to that engine control panel
告诉我哪些继电器过载了
and tell me which relays are in overload position.
快说你看到了什么
What does it look like in there?
好像是某种电器设备
It seems to run on some form of electricity.
地球人都知道
Well, you're not wrong.
班纳 我们是友不是敌
We are not your enemies, Banner.
清醒过来吧
Try to think!
继电器没问题了
Okay, the relays are intact.
然后干嘛
What's our next move?
就算我把残骸都清走了
Even if I clear the rotors,
没有助力转子也无法启动
this thing won't re-engage without a jump.
我得进去推着它转
I'm going to have to get in there and push.
转速一起来 就会把你绞成肉泥
If that thing gets up to speed, you'll get shredded.
那你就扳动控制器
That stator control unit
这样磁极就会反转
can reverse the polarity long enough
直至磁悬浮解除…
to disengage maglev and that could...
说人话
Speak English!
看到红色的控制杆了吗
You see that red lever?
能让转子减速 给我飞出来的时间
It will slow the rotors down long enough for me to get out.
待在那儿等我指令
Stand by it. Wait for my word.
撤离下层飞机库甲板上的全部人员
We need full evac on the lower hangar bay.
小心手雷
Grenade!
有人入侵
We've got a perimeter breach!
神盾设施内有敌人
Hostiles are in S.H.I.E.L.D. Gear.
全体人员注意
Call-outs at every junction.
绿巨人和托尔在4层研发层
We have the Hulk and Thor on Research Level 4.
2和3层摄像头损坏
Levels 2 and 3 are dark.
长官 绿巨人会把这里彻底毁掉的
Sir, the Hulk will tear this place apart!
那就调虎离山
Get his attention.
60护航机前往Y型区 火力牵制敌人
Escort 6-0, proceed to Wishbone and engage hostile.
保持距离
Don't get too close.
收到
Copy.
看到目标
Target acquired.
开火
Target engaged.
目标火了 他发火了
Target angry, target angry!
他们又没来过这儿 怎么这么轻车熟路的
They're not getting through here, so what the hell...
(一号引擎出现故障)
一号引擎停机了
Engine one is now in shut-down.
我们在失控下降
We are in an uncontrolled descent.
长官 一号引擎彻底停转
Sir, we've lost all power in engine one.
是巴顿 他毁了我们的系统
It's Barton. He took out our systems.
他去关押层了
He's headed for the detention level.
有人听到吗
Does anybody copy?
我是罗曼诺夫探员
This is Agent Romanoff.
收到
I copy.
斯塔克 航母在下降
Stark, we're losing altitude.
发现了
Yeah, I noticed.
不
No!
你可真是记吃不记打
Are you ever not going to fall for that?
人类认为我们有不死之身
The humans think us immortal.
检验一下吧
Should we test that?
到那边去
Move away, please.
帅不
You like this?
因为你的毁灭者 我们研发了这个的原型机
We started working on the prototype after you sent the Destroyer.
我都不清楚它的威力
Even I don't know what it does.
想试试吗
Do you want to find out?
不
No!
娜塔莎
Natasha?
你必输无疑
You're going to lose.
是嘛
Am I?
是你本性使然
It's in your nature.
你们那些英雄被杀得七零八落
Your heroes are scattered.
你们的飞堡行将陨落
Your floating fortress falls from the sky.
你怎么看出败局的
Where is my disadvantage?
你没有信念
You lack conviction.
我看我...
I don't think I'm...
这么威武啊
So, that's what it does.
高度
所有人员立即前往紧急中心
All hands to crash stations immediately.
队长 扳控制杆
Cap, hit the lever.
暂时不太方便
I need a minute here!
扳控制杆
Lever
快点
now!
救救兄弟
Help!
对不起 头儿
Sorry, boss.
斑比逃了
The god rabbited.
保持清醒
Just stay awake.
看着我
Eyes on me.
不行了 我得离岗了
No, I'm clocking out here.
不批准
Not an option.
没事 头儿
It's okay, boss.
想要他们成为真正的团队
This was never gonna work
就得给他们点…
if they didn't have something
动…
to...
科尔森探员殉职了
Agent Coulson is down.
医疗队正在赶去
A medical team is on its way to your location.
已经到了
They're here.
他们宣布死亡了
They called it.
这些卡片揣在菲尔·科尔森的外衣口袋里
These were in Phil Coulson's jacket.
看来他没要到你的签名
I guess he never did get you to sign them.
我们现在耳聋眼瞎 一筹莫展
We're dead in the air up here.
通讯中断 魔方下落不明
Our communications, the location of the Cube,
还弄丢了班纳和托尔
Banner, Thor...
我没辙了
I got nothing for you.
最得力手下也牺牲了
I lost my one good eye.
也许是我自找的
Maybe I had that coming.
没错
Yes,
我们是想将宇宙魔方用于制武
we were going to build an arsenal with the Tesseract.
但我就没把宝都压在这事上
I never put all my chips on that number, though,
因为我还有个更大胆的计划
because I was playing something even riskier.
我有个设想 这事斯塔克知道
There was an idea, Stark knows this,
叫做"复仇者计划"
called the Avengers Initiative.
就是将一些能力超群的人召集起来
The idea was to bring together a group of remarkable people
看他们所组成的团队能否更加强大
to see if they could become something more.
看他们能否在危急时刻并肩战斗
To see if they could work together when we needed them to,
赢得那些我们赢不了的战争
to fight the battles that we never could.
菲尔·科尔森到死都相信这个设想
Phil Coulson died still believing in that idea.
相信英雄
In heroes.
好吧
Well,
这观念的确过时了
it's an old-fashioned notion.
你从天而降
You fell out of the sky.
我伤着谁了吗
Did I hurt anybody?
这附近就没人
There's nobody around here to get hurt.
不过你把鸽子都吓坏了
You did scare the hell out of some pigeons, though.
那真走运
Lucky.
或者是你瞄得准
Or just good aim.
落下来时你还醒着呢
You were awake when you fell.
- 你都看见了 - 都看到了
- You saw? - The whole thing.
你穿透屋顶摔下来
Right through the ceiling.
大大的 绿绿的 还光着屁股
Big and green and buck-ass nude.
给
Here.
我估计得等你缩到常人的身材
Didn't think those would fit you until you shrunk down
才能穿上这衣服
to a regular-size feller.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是外星人吗
Are you an alien?
什么
What?
你是外太空来的人吗
From outer space, an alien.
不是
No.
那你这娃可有病啊
Well, then, son, you've got a condition.
克林特 你会没事的
Clint. You're going to be all right.
是吗
You know that?
你确定吗
Is that what you know?
不能放松
I've got no window.
得把他赶出来
I have to flush him out.
这可不容易 得慢慢来
You got to level out. It's going to take time.
你不懂
You don't understand.
你知道被人夺去意志 肆意摆布的滋味吗
Have you ever had someone take your brain and play?
把你拽出来 把别人放进去
Pull you out and stuff something else in?
你知道被瓦解的感觉吗
Do you know what it's like to be unmade?
你明知我了解那种感受
You know that I do.
我怎么恢复的
Why am I back?
你怎么把他弄出去的
How did you get him out?
认知重校
Cognitive recalibration.
俗称敲脑瓜
I hit you really hard on the head.
谢谢
Thanks.
娜塔莎
Natasha...
我杀了多少探…
How many agents did I...
别
Don't.
别去折磨自己 克林特
Don't do that to yourself, Clint.
作恶的是洛基
This is Loki.
是怪物 是魔法
This is monsters and magic,
是我们闻所未闻的敌人
and nothing we were ever trained for.
洛基 他跑了吗
Loki, did he get away?
跑了
Yeah.
你知道他去哪了吗
I don't suppose you know where.
轮不到我多管
I didn't need to know.
也就没问
I didn't ask.
不过他很快就会行动了
He's going to make his play soon, though.
就在今天
Today.
我们得阻止他
We got to stop him.
是吗 谁是我们
Yeah? Who's "we"?
不知道 活下来的人吧
I don't know. Whoever's left.
哼
Well,
要是我能一箭射穿洛基的眼窝
if I put an arrow through Loki's eye socket,
也能睡好觉了
I would sleep better, I suppose.
这话才像你
Now you sound like you.
可你不像你
But you don't.
你是间谍 不是士兵
You're a spy, not a soldier.
怎么会想去冲锋陷阵
Now you want to wade into a war. Why?
洛基把你怎么了
What did Loki do to you?
没怎么 我只是…
He didn't. I just...
娜塔莎
Natasha.
我被他说动了
I've been compromised.
我欠了血债
I got red in my ledger.
想要还掉
I would like to wipe it out.
他成家了吗
Was he married?
没有
No.
有个女友 好像是大提琴手
There was a cellist, I think.
真可惜
I'm sorry.
他看着人不错
He seemed like a good man.
他就是个傻瓜
He was an idiot.
怎么 就因为他有信仰吗
Why? For believing?
因为他独自去跟洛基叫板
For taking on Loki alone.
那叫尽职尽责
He was doing his job.
那叫自不量力 他该等支援
He was out of his league. He should have waited.
他该…
He should have...
有时候就是没别的办法 托尼
Sometimes there isn't a way out, Tony.
是啊 这话挺耳熟
Right, I've heard that before.
这是你第一次失去战友吗
Is this the first time you lost a soldier?
我们不是战士
We are not soldiers.
我不会听令于弗瑞
I'm not marching to Fury's fife.
我也不会
Neither am I.
他也该为洛基犯下的罪行负责
He's got the same blood on his hands that Loki does.
但那些我们得先放放
But right now, we got to put that behind us
对付外敌
and get this done.
洛基需要一个能量源
Loki needs a power source.
要是我们能列出…
If we can put together a list...
他把大战弄成了私仇
He made it personal.
那不是重点
That's not the point.
这就是重点 这就是洛基的目的
That is the point. That's Loki's point.
他干嘛直捣我们的老巢
He hit us all right where we live. Why?
好击溃我们
To tear us apart.
是啊 分散击破的确是妙计
Yeah, divide and conquer is great
但他知道我们是他大业的绊脚石 对吧
but he knows he has to take us out to win, right?
这才是他的心结
That's what he wants.
他想打败我们 还要别人看着他赢
He wants to beat us, he wants to be seen doing it.
他想要观众
He wants an audience.
对了 我在斯图加特就正碰上他的表演
Right. I caught his act in Stuttgart.
没错 那只是试映 这是…
Yeah, that was just previews.
这可是首演之夜
This is opening night.
洛基就是这场戏的主角
And Loki, he's a full-tilt diva, right?
他要人给他献花 还要四处招摇
He wants flowers, he wants parades.
他要一座高耸入云的纪念碑 上面刻着他的名字
He wants a monument built to the skies with his name plastered...
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
(斯塔克)
该走了
Time to go.
- 去哪 - 路上说
- Go where? - I'll tell you on the way.
你会开飞机吗
Can you fly one of those jets?
我会
I can.
你有战衣吗
You got a suit?
有
Yeah.
那就去穿
Then suit up.
未经允许你们不得登机
Hey, you guys aren't authorised to be in here.
孩子 省省吧
Son, just don't.
长官
Sir.
希尔探员
Agent Hill.
那些卡片
Those cards,
是放在科尔森的衣柜里 而不是外衣
they were in Coulson's locker, not in his jacket.
他们需要点动力
They needed the push.
6号停机坪有人私自起飞
We have an unauthorised departure from Bay 6.
他们找到洛基了
They found him.
想尽一切办法恢复通讯
Get our communications back up, whatever you have to do.
- 我要监控全局 - 遵命 长官
- I want eyes on everything. - Yes, sir.
先生 我已关闭方舟反应堆
Sir, I've turned off the arc reactor
但那个装置已能自续供能了
but the device is already self-sustaining.
关掉它 塞尔维格博士
Shut it down, Dr Selvig.
太迟了
It's too late!
现在没法停了
She can't stop now.
她有东西要给我们看
She wants to show us something!
一个新宇宙
A new universe.
随便你
Okay.
那层屏障是纯能量
The barrier is pure energy.
无法打破
It's unbreachable.
看出来了
Yeah, I got that.
换招
Plan B.
先生 马克7型尚不能调用
Sir, the Mark 7 is not ready for deployment.
那就不要轮子了 我们没时间了
Then skip the spinning rims. We're on the clock.
你是来求我发慈悲的吗
Please tell me you're going to appeal to my humanity.
其实我是来吓唬你的
Actually, I'm planning to threaten you.
那你可不该把铁甲脱了
You should have left your armour on for that.
是啊
Yeah.
不过感觉穿上也没用
It's seen a bit of mileage,
毕竟你拿着终结者型蓝杖呢
and you've got the glow stick of destiny.
来一杯吗
Would you like a drink?
拖时间是没用的
Stalling me won't change anything.
不不不 是吓唬
No, no. Threatening.
真不喝吗
No drink? Are you sure?
我可要来一杯
I'm having one.
齐塔瑞大军要来了 谁都休想阻止
The Chitauri are coming. Nothing will change that.
我还怕什么
What have I to fear?
复仇者联盟
The Avengers.
我们给自己起的名字 就是个团队
That's what we call ourselves. We're sort of like a team.
全球最猛的英雄什么的
"Earth's mightiest heroes" type thing.
见过了 不过如此
Yes, I've met them.
好吧
Yeah.
我承认磨合是花了些时间
It takes us a while to get any traction, I'll give you that one.
不过我们来数数吧
But let's do a head count, here.
我们有你的半神老哥
Your brother, the demigod,
一名超级大兵
a super soldier,
不负盛名的活传奇
a living legend who kind of lives up to the legend.
一个发起脾气能吓死人的人
A man with breathtaking anger-management issues,
两个顶级刺客 而你小子
a couple of master assassins, and you, big fella,
把他们都惹恼了
you've managed to piss off every single one of them.
我就是这么打算的
That was the plan.
我看你是没想清楚
Not a great plan.
等他们来了
When they come,
放心 他们会来的
and they will,
那就是冤有头债有主
they'll come for you.
我有一支大军
I have an army.
我们有绿巨人
We have a Hulk.
那野兽不是跑丢了吗
I thought the beast had wandered off.
重点不在那儿 你别做皇帝梦了
You're missing the point. There is no throne.
你是绝不可能称王称霸的
There is no version of this where you come out on top.
或许你大军降至 或许我们抵挡不了
Maybe your army comes and maybe it's too much for us,
但帐都会记到你头上
but it's all on you.
我们要是保护不了地球
Because if we can't protect the Earth,
绝对会为之复仇
you can be damn well sure we'll avenge it.
要是他们忙着打你
How will your friends have time for me
哪有时间陪我玩
when they are so busy fighting you?
以前没出过问题啊
This usually works.
性能失常神马的 也不算罕见啦
Well, performance issues, it's not uncommon.
五个男人就有一个…
One out of five...
贾维斯 随时可以了
Jarvis, anytime now.
你们都会败在我脚下
You will all fall before me.
调用
Deploy!
快点的
你还惹恼了一个人
And there's one other person you pissed off.
他叫菲尔
His name was Phil.
好吧
Right.
大军来了
Army.
洛基
Loki!
关掉宇宙魔方 不然我毁了它
Turn off the Tesseract, or I'll destroy it.
你毁不掉
You can't.
停不下来了
There is no stopping it.
现在只能
There is only
开战
the war.
那就来吧
So be it.
斯塔克 我们在三点钟方向 航向东北
Stark, we're on your three, headed northeast.
我说你们还去买外卖了吗
What? Did you stop for drive-through?
上帕克大街 我引他们过去给你们当靶子
Swing up Park. I'm going to lay them out for you.
先生 又来人了
Sir, we have more incoming.
好吧 去招呼招呼他们
Fine. Let's keep them occupied.
- 小娜 - 我看见他了
- Nat? - I see him.
我们得回上面去
We got to get back up there.
斯塔克 看见这怪物了吗
Stark, are you seeing this?
看见了 还不敢相信
Seeing. Still working on believing.
班纳来了吗
Where's Banner? Has he shown up yet?
班纳
Banner?
他到了就告诉我
Just keep me posted.
贾维斯 找到这东西的软肋
Jarvis, find me a soft spot.
你瞧啊
Look at this!
瞧瞧这一切
Look around you!
你以为你称了王 杀戮就会结束吗
You think this madness will end with your rule?
太迟了
It's too late.
想阻止也来不及了
It's too late to stop it.
来得及 兄弟齐心 其利断金
No. We can, together.
妇人之仁
Sentiment.
有平民被困在…
We've got civilians still trapped up here.
洛基
Loki.
他们在下面只有挨打的份儿
They're fish in a barrel down there.
这边有我们 没问题的 你走吧
We got this. It's good. Go.
你挡得住他们吗
Do you think you can hold them off?
队长
Captain,
我乐意之至
it would be my genuine pleasure.
跟布达佩斯那次一模一样
Just like Budapest all over again.
我们想的一定不是一个布达佩斯
You and I remember Budapest very differently.
国民警卫队集结
It's going to be an hour
需要一小时
before they can scramble the National Guard.
国民警卫队
National Guard?
军队知道这边发生了什么吗
Does the army know what's happening here?
我们知道吗
Do we?
派人进这几栋楼
You need men in these buildings.
楼里的人可能会慌不择路地
There are people inside and they're going to be running
撞到枪口上
right into the line of fire.
你带他们走地下室或者地铁
You take them to the basements or through the subway.
别让他们到街上来
You keep them off the streets.
一直到39大街全部封锁
I need a perimeter as far back as 39th.
我凭什么听你的
Why the hell should I take orders from you?
派人进这几栋楼
I need men in those buildings.
把人往地下带 别到街上来
Lead the people down and away from the streets.
一直到39大街
We're going to set up a
要全部封锁
perimeter all the way down to 39th Street.
好吧 这下它盯上我了
Well, we got its attention.
然后怎么办
What the hell was step two?
上面怎么样了
What's the story upstairs?
包围魔方的能量无法穿透
The power surrounding the Cube is impenetrable.
托尔说得对 我们得先对付这些怪物
Thor's right. We got to deal with these guys.
- 怎么对付 - 齐心协力
- How do we do this? - As a team.
我跟洛基还有帐要算
I have unfinished business with Loki.
是吗 排个号吧
Yeah? Well, get in line.
别闹了
Save it.
洛基会把战斗集中在我们身上
Loki's going to keep this fight focused on us,
这样正好
and that's what we need.
没有他控制着 场面会更乱
Without him, these things could run wild.
斯塔克在上面 他会需要我们…
We got Stark up top. He's going to need us to...
看起来挺吓人
So, this all seems horrible.
我见过更吓人的
I've seen worse.
真抱歉
Sorry.
没事 我们正需要能吓住人的队友
No, we could use a little worse.
- 斯塔克 他来了 - 班纳吗
- Stark, we got him. - Banner?
被你说中了
Just like you said.
让他"变装" 我这就把好戏拉过去演
Then tell him to suit up. I'm bringing the party to you.
这有什么"好"的
I don't see how that's a party.
班纳博士
Dr Banner.
你现在可以发火了
Now might be a really good time for you to get angry.
这就是我的绝招 队长
That's my secret, Captain.
我一直窝着火呢
I'm always angry.
撑住
Hold on!
派出余部
Send the rest.
大伙儿
Guys.
下命令吧 队长
Call it, Captain.
好 都注意了
All right, listen up.
如果不能关掉传送门 就得控制住局面
Until we can close that portal, our priority is containment.
巴顿 上那个屋顶
Barton, I want you on that roof.
眼观八方 把大部和散兵的行踪都报出来
Eyes on everything. Call out patterns and strays.
斯塔克 你守着封锁线
Stark, you got the perimeter.
凡是跑出三个街区的东西
Anything gets more than three blocks out,
要么给赶回来 要么给灭了
you turn it back or you turn it to ash.
- 送我一程好吗 - 好
- Can you give me a lift? - Right.
抓紧了 精灵小王子
Better clench up, Legolas.
托尔 你得去想办法堵上传送门
Thor, you got to try and bottleneck that portal.
减缓他们进军
Slow them down.
你不是能打闪吗 打着这帮混球
You got the lightning. Light the bastards up.
你和我 我们留在地面
You and me, we stay here on the ground.
牵制兵力
We keep the fighting here.
绿巨人
And Hulk...
使劲砸
Smash.
长官
Sir.
理事会来电
The Council is on.
斯塔克 你后面可跟了不少敌人
Stark, you got a lot of strays sniffing your tail.
我是不想让他们到街上去
I'm just trying to keep them off the streets.
他们不会拐弯
Well, they can't bank worth a damn.
找个死角
So find a tight corner.
好的 收到
I will roger that.
真烦人
Oh, boy.
指挥得好
Nice call.
还有什么
What else you got?
托尔在6大街跟一支飞行队干起来了
Thor is taking on a squadron down on Sixth.
居然不带我玩
And he didn't invite me.
队长 如果不关上传送门
Captain, none of this is going to mean a damn thing
我们这么打也没用
if we don't close that portal.
什么武器都伤不了它
Our biggest guns couldn't touch it.
或许得想别的办法
Well, maybe it's not about guns.
想上去得找人捎你一道
If you want to get up there, you're going to need a ride.
我知道找谁
I got a ride.
不过你得推我一把
I could use a boost, though.
你真要这么干吗
Are you sure about this?
是啊 肯定特带劲
Yeah. It's gonna be fun.
转弯 转弯 快转啊
Okay, turn, turn.
队长 42大街上过了麦迪逊大街的银行
Captain, the bank on 42nd past Madison.
很多平民被敌人困在那里面
They've cornered a lot of civilians in there.
我这就去
I'm on it.
大家让开
Everyone! Clear out!
弗瑞局长
Director Fury,
理事会已做出决定
the Council has made a decision.
这我知道了
I recognise the Council has made a decision.
但鉴于这决定蠢到家了
But given that it's a stupid-ass decision,
我打算不予理睬
I have elected to ignore it.
局长 你的航母离那里最近
Director, you're closer than any of our subs.
立刻派出战机
You scramble that jet...
议员 那可是曼哈顿岛
That is the island of Manhattan, Councilman.
除非我的小分队确实撑不住了
Until I'm certain my team can't hold it,
我不会下令对平民百姓
I will not order a nuclear strike
实施核打击
against a civilian population.
如果不在那儿消灭他们 世界都要遭殃
If we don't hold them here, we lose everything.
派出核战机才真的无法挽回
If I send that bird out, we already have.
是你啊
You.
鹰眼
Hawkeye!
小娜 你干什么呢
Nat, what are you doing?
帮帮我啊
A little help?
瞧我的
I got him.
够了
Enough!
你们都算什么东西
You are, all of you, beneath me!
我可是神 你这蠢货
I am a god, you dull creature.
你这蚂蚁休想欺辱我…
And I will not be bullied by...
弱爆了
Puny god.
权杖
The sceptre...
博士
Doctor.
洛基的权杖 它的能量
Loki's sceptre. The energy.
宇宙魔方无力抵抗
The Tesseract can't fight,
它不能抵挡它自身的攻击
but you can't protect against yourself.
别自责了
It's not your fault.
你不知道自己在做什么
You didn't know what you were doing.
其实 我好像知道
Actually, I think I did.
我安了个可以切断能量源的保险装置
I built in a safety to cut their power source.
洛基的权杖
Loki's sceptre.
或许能关闭传送门
It may be able to close the portal.
它就在那儿
And I'm looking right at it.
先生 我们所剩能量不够穿透它的外壳
Sir, we will lose power before we penetrate that shell.
贾维斯 你听过约拿的故事吗
Jarvis, you ever hear the tale of Jonah?
我觉得他可不是好榜样
I wouldn't consider him a role model.
弗瑞局长已被解除指挥权
Director Fury is no longer in command.
代行命令 7A11
Override order 7-Alpha-1-1.
7A11命令确认 我们可以起飞
7-Alpha-1-1, confirmed. We're go for takeoff.
长官 有架战机起动了
Sir, we have a bird in motion!
甲板上的人员请注意抗命战机
Anyone on the deck, we have a rogue bird.
得阻止它起飞
We need to shut it down!
重复 起飞未经许可
Repeat, takeoff is not authorised.
斯塔克 听见了吗
Stark, do you hear me?
有枚导弹直奔你那儿去了
You have a missile headed straight for the city.
多久到
How long?
最多三分钟
Three minutes, max.
载着核弹 能将市中心夷为平地
The payload will wipe out Midtown.
贾维斯 将所剩动力全部输至推进器
Jarvis, put everything we got into the thrusters.
输好了
I just did.
核弹已投
Package is sent.
从现在起两分三十秒后爆炸
Detonation in 2 minutes, 30 seconds, mark.
准备好继续迎战了吗
Are you ready for another bout?
怎么 你要睡着了吗
What, are you getting sleepy?
对准顶部
Right at the crown!
我能关掉它
I can close it.
你们听见了吗
Can anybody copy?
我能关掉传送门
I can shut the portal down.
- 那就关啊 - 别 等等
- Do it! - No, wait.
斯塔克 敌人还在不断涌入
Stark, these things are still coming.
有枚核弹正往这儿飞
I got a nuke coming in.
会在一分钟内爆炸
It's gonna blow in less than a minute.
我已经想好该把它送哪去了
And I know just where to put it.
斯塔克 你的能量不够往回走了
Stark, you know that's a one-way trip.
留着能量拐弯吧 小贾
Save the rest for the turn, J.
先生 要我给波茨小姐打电话吗
Sir, shall I try Miss Potts?
也好
Might as well.
纽约街道成了战场
The streets of New York City have become a battleground.
重大新闻 曼哈顿市中心遭袭
军队已赶到 并努力压制敌军
The Army is here trying to contain the violence
但显然力不从心
but clearly, it is outmatched.
我得承认 我入行以来
And I have to say, in all my years of reporting,
还没见过这样的事
I have never seen anything like this.
我们尚不了解这支小分队
We have limited information on the team
但能认出亿万富翁托尼·斯塔克 也就是钢铁侠
but we do know that billionaire Tony Stark's Iron Man...
(呼叫失败)
快回来啊 斯塔克
Come on, Stark.
关门吧
Close it.
你小子行啊
Son of a gun.
他根本没减速
He's not slowing down.
他还有呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
搞什么啊
What the hell?
怎么回事
What just happened?
没人给我人工呼吸吧
Please tell me nobody kissed me.
我们胜利了
We won.
好诶
All right, yay!
万岁 干得好 伙计们
Hurray. Good job, guys.
我们明天别来上班了 给自己放假一天
Let's just not come in tomorrow. Let's just take a day.
吃过土耳其烤肉吗
Have you ever tried shawarma?
离这儿两条街有家土耳其烤肉店
There's a shawarma joint about two blocks from here.
其实我没吃过 但我想尝尝
I don't know what it is, but I want to try it.
还没结束呢
We're not finished yet.
那待会儿去
And then shawarma after.
如果你们不介意
If it's all the same to you,
我现在想来一杯
I'll have that drink now.
尽管城市饱受摧残
Despite the devastation
在这起已证实为外星入侵的袭击事件中
of what has been confirmed as an extraterrestrial attack,
这支名为复仇者联盟的
the extraordinary heroics
小队的英雄壮举
of the group known as the Avengers
对很多人来说不仅是个安慰
has been to many a cause not only for comfort,
更值得庆祝
but for celebration.
知道他们的存在真是太好了
It's just really great knowing they're out there.
有人在守护着我们
That someone is watching over us.
我爱你 托尔
I love you, Thor!
那些怪物一通乱打
And then these guys were like...
到处在爆炸
And then the air goes...
然后那个绿色的家伙就…
And this green guy walks up and he goes...
说不清
I don't know.
这些家伙的存在让我觉得不安全
I don't exactly feel safer with those things out there.
我就是有种被蒙在鼓里的感觉
It just seems that there's a lot they're not telling us.
纽约有超级英雄 少来了
Superheroes in New York? Give me a break.
这些所谓的英雄
These so-called "Heroes"
必须为城市的损毁负责
have to be held responsible for the destruction done to this city.
他们打完了仗 都跑哪去了
This was their fight. Where are they now?
人们对复仇者联盟充满好奇
Tough questions are being asked about the Avengers themselves.
然而他们却来如风 去无影
Their sudden appearance and equally sudden disappearance...
怎么 这事倒怪罪给他们了
What, this is all somehow their fault?
美国队长是我的救命恩人
Captain America saved my life.
不管他在哪 不管他们都身处何方
Wherever he is, and wherever any of them are,
我只想
I would just...
我只想说声谢谢
I would want to say thank you.
复仇者都去哪了
Where are the Avengers?
我暂时没去追查他们的行踪
I'm not currently tracking their whereabouts.
依我看他们有权休假
I'd say they've earned a leave of absence.
宇宙魔方呢
And the Tesseract?
宇宙魔方已完璧归赵
The Tesseract is where it belongs.
我们不能染指
Out of our reach.
你无权做这种决定
That's not your call.
决定不是我做的
I didn't make it.
我只是没跟做这决定的神较劲
I just didn't argue with the god that did.
那你就让他带走了魔方
So, you let him take it
和本该为他的罪行受到制裁的战犯洛基
and the war criminal, Loki, who should be answering for his crime.
我想他会受到制裁的
I think he will be.
我看你没意识到你这样做的后果
I don't think you understand what you've started,
就这么让复仇者回到社会上
letting the Avengers loose on this world.
他们都是危险人物
They're dangerous.
确实 他们的威名不仅传遍天下
They surely are, and the whole world knows it.
更声振寰宇
Every world knows it.
这不正是我们的目的吗
Was that the point of all this?
宣告我们不好欺负
A statement?
是人若犯我 我必犯人
A promise.
长官 往后怎么办
Sir, how does it work now?
他们各走各的了
They've gone their separate ways.
有的人还去了很远的地方
Some, pretty extremely far.
再遇到这种情况
If we get into a situation like this again,
我们怎么办
what happens then?
他们还会回来
They'll come back.
你有这把握吗
Are you really sure about that?
有
I am.
为什么
Why?
因为我们需要他们回来
Because we'll need them to.
人类
Humans.
并不像他说的那样懦弱卑微
They are not the cowering wretches we were promised.
他们坚守家园
They stand.
不能被驾驭 不甘受统治
They are unruly, and therefore cannot be ruled.
与他们为敌
To challenge them
无异于求死
is to court death.